# DINAKAR VEMPATI

#### **Data Scientist**

Hyderabad, Telangana

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/DINAKAR-VEMPATI/aa4c99d7789ed2b2

Experienced and dedicated Data Scientist with several years of experience identifying efficiencies and problem areas within data streams, while communicating needs for projects. Committed to helping companies advance by helping them to develop strategic plans based on predictive modeling and findings.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

## Work Experience

#### **Data Scientist**

Glosoft Technologies Pvt Ltd - Bengaluru, Karnataka November 2019 to Present

- MySQL, Data Cleaning, Features scaling, Features engineering using Pandas and NumPy packages in python.
- Task automation using macros and VBA, creating dynamic reports with PivotTables, building formulas, Cell formatting, Managing large datasets with functions: IF, SUM, INDEX, MATCH, VLOOKUP
- Building charts and graphs, Pivot tables and reporting, Data recording, VLOOKUP and XLOOKUP, Advanced conditional formatting.
- Data simulations, Data validation, Charts and graphs creation, Visualization and Dashboards creations.
- Data Normalization, Regression Models like Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, KNN, Random Forest Linear Regression.
- Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs.
- Coordinated statistical data analysis, design and information flow.
- Utilized exploratory data analysis techniques to identify patterns, relationships, and trends.
- Created reports and statistical analysis as required.
- Utilized algorithmic and programming tools to build helpful predictive models.

#### **Business Manager**

Ardis Enviro Solutions - Hyderabad, Telangana August 2015 to November 2019

- Gathering data from Marketing and Sales team regularly, understanding the data, cleaning it with use of pandas.
- Information gathering through web-scrapping of various websites of respective industries.
- Brought in new business connections and revenue generation opportunities by improving networking strategies.
- Oversaw office operations for organization by processing vital documentation, obtaining insurance verification and authorization for services.
- Served as a successful leader, promoting and achieving store success.

### Education

### **MBA** in Engineering

University of Mysore - Mysore, Karnataka April 2013 to May 2015

## **Bachelor's degree in Electrical Engineering**

SRM University - Chennai, Tamil Nadu March 2009 to April 2013

## Skills / IT Skills

- Pandas
- Scipy
- Excellent Interpersonal
- Ability to work in a Team
- Machine Learning and Mathematical skills
- Adaptability
- Python
- Statistics
- MS Visual Studio
- Tableau
- Deep Learning
- MySQL
- Quick Problem Solving
- Microsoft Excel
- JupyterNotebook skills
- Tolerant and flexible
- Strong Analytical, Logical
- Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Natural Language
- Numpy Processing
- · Organisational skills
- Microsoft Office
- Communication skills
- Leadership

### Online Profile

http://linkedin.com/in/dinakar-v-8a620aa9